right welcome to the solution raising on
gamepedia I don't this is my first time
meeting with either of you so this
should be an interesting meeting I'm
really excited to see you both here
if anyone but I've always offer it for
other people to start but I'm always
happy to start what do you think is
going on currently in gaming
what brings you I guess I can stop that
Dooley hi mark we just got started so
we're just sharing what we what our
current um vision of game a is why do we
want a game beat anyway so what is
currently happening in the world okay
but just let you know like they teach at
10:30 so I'm gonna this is I'm very
interested in hearing what you guys come
up with
so who's gone I'm just gonna sit there
and listen for a little bit okay sounds
good we can also just mute ourselves
because it right yeah so I was sharing
my kiss experience at game area yeah so
um I guess hi my name is Kyle my live in
London and I kind of stumbled on to gain
be a couple of weeks ago and it's been
something that the concept has been
around in kind of my awareness for
several years but I had realized there
was a thing called Debbie so you know in
in terms of my experience of what does
it what gets what has led me to be
interested in lists it feels like we're
reaching a point of paralysis in terms
of being able to make decisions you sort
of you see it out in like the big wide
world and terms like
for example the American political
system but then you know even in
microcosm within like organizations it
seems like we want to move towards more
humane methods of organization but
that's my profession I work in sort of
project management operations but
equally it feels that we don't have the
the cognitive tools to do that and so I
started to get interested in like how
might we develop those tools and that's
where I wound up I just uh Marco so if
you want to share before you you pop out
if you need to that is awesome
to me and my mom is over here with me -
off camera we also just stumbled on some
YouTube videos and that's how we found
out about game B but like Carl said like
that the thought of something like this
existing was already stuff we talked
about we just didn't know where it was
or how to find it you know and um I
guess game a feels like we're just
pieces in a game where the people in
charge they just like feed off us for
their their interest their money and
their power and really what we need and
want they don't really care about you
know and the thought of a society
existing that really was about what
people really want and what people
really need and how people really want
to live you know is something that we
would love to be a part of you know so
we're really interested in finding
more about this and um I'm a mental
health care worker so you know I see how
the way that game a operates really
destroys people you know from the
outside in and that really bothers me so
here I am
thank you I'll share my what brings me
to game be game a what I was calling
capitalism but really it's so much more
than that it's everything that's that's
going on it's the meta-crisis it's our
environmental degradation it's our
mental health crisis our disconnection
our disempowerment that we leave it up
to the 1% to to solve everything and
they're doing it in a horrible way for
their own benefit and we're all paying a
price for that and long before I came
into game B I had a vision for how I
thought we could come and solve the
world together which was basically a
technological cooperative and incoming
through game game B realizing all of the
blind spots I had and just start playing
in this space just start playing in what
can we create together and that's her
solution raisings
came from and I'm really excited cuz
because this my version of how we create
game B is kind of this exact solution
raising we don't need to we can agree
that game is broken and we don't even
need to agree why it's broken but we can
talk about it you know and then we can
talk about our beautiful version of what
game B could be and they don't need to
match what we do need to agree on what
we can come to consensus on is a
powerful step forward it solves it for
us the you know the 10,000 people
theoretically and so I'm super excited
to have this conversation and I do think
there may be I try to in this section
list some things that are positive about
whatever we're talking about and so in
this space
I do think game a what we are currently
doing what's happening with Kovan 19
there is beautiful stuff emerging that
people are coming together they're
starting to wake up on mass and that can
be very uncomfortable and also very
powerful and so and we've had a lot of
innovation and and forward movement we
haven't done it in a way that's
equitable for everyone right our
standard of living has increased our
technology has increased but the gap has
widened and our health gap has widened
and our education gap has widened and so
finding ways to come together and solve
things without leaving them up to the
big other is what I am passionate about
and so and now we can if Mark wants to
share he's he's free to and also then we
can just unmute and have a little bit of
an open conversation about current
gaming before we switch on to our
beautiful version of gamey yeah thanks
Julian thanks Carl and uh I always like
to listen just to try and get a picture
in like a feel for where where people
are coming from
I feel being a very very personal level
it's it's for me it's it's the decisions
I know and the things I've been involved
with where I know I look back and go oh
well why did that feel wrong it felt
wrong because I know that it would
ripple out and make things worse in the
world eventually and I would always like
I think I've had that for a long time so
I I've wrestled with that and I found
myself out of place in groups where I've
wanted to go with this one feeling and
and then went with this other one and
one why I did that when I saw the people
doing that and they saw you know we
talked about one percentage that's where
it gets magnified but I know I have my
own what he called it that that I've
contributed to that so I I found game B
as a relief that other people were
trying to move towards that one way of
being instead of this other way of you
and I think this is just a way to
magnify I agree with Jubilee and that's
why I love this thing that she's created
because it's going to be one bill
approaches that kind of go here here and
there and then move forward but it'll be
with the same feeling right this feeling
that there's a there's a better way to
do it then
what's manifesting in ourselves and
magnified not there
so unfortunately Linda can't hear mark
and I don't know how to actually solve
that try going out and back in Linda
that's literally my only life turn it
off and on and see if we can because I
could hear him and hopefully the
recording can hear him perfect and then
see if that that works and then like I
said we can unmute for this portion and
have it all the conversation which will
be a little harder if we can't hear one
another for sure I think that's very
game a spike let's have a conversation
but let's not hear each other yeah I'm
gonna quite noisy where I am so I'm
gonna keep yeah so how do we have we
start myself a bit of an open
conversation as to game a this is only
give 15 minutes to this portion cuz this
is what we concentrate on for all of
life right what's wrong what's wrong
with society and then moving on to the
adjacent possible there is a lot that's
wrong with gaming and that's what brings
us to this this portion for me it's the
environmental I think is is the biggest
reason it's the one that feels most
immediate most we don't have a lot of
time before dealing with that and the
more I get into desperation around it
the less I'm capable of doing anything
about it focus an individual and I think
as a society as well so to be able to
create safety and happiness for myself
and for the people work you know I'm
creating game B and then having that
spread out to the rest of the world is
more and more the solution that I'm
living in - yeah I mean the environment
thing is interesting I had this
interesting line today there is that
we're kind of optimizing everything to
convert the environment into dollars
into dollars earn to things that can be
measured in dollars and I guess when it
I look good like my own kind of interest
in the sphere as well it's like where we
get safes with measuring things when we
get it to say
with like business generating value or
is this generating profit or whatever we
get like total tunnel vision and then we
wind up throwing out all the good things
that go along with say for example the
environment or treating people humanely
us and I think you mark just when I
pause for a second just done you I mean
not unpause it's so that we can see if
Linda can hear you well you know what if
you're only here for seven minutes I
would like to go on to the next part
then because I would love to hear your
version of what game B looks like to you
they do not need to match what is your
beautiful future that you are living in
- I guess well for me it's more into
that feeling of what game B is so where
where I have that feeling of this is
this feels like it's good over here but
what I'm doing this over here and and I
see I in business and and bigger
business and just in groups of people
you can see that there's there's some
kind of they have a they have an
awareness of what is best for for them
in the future and them others in the
future and just to build a better world
they want but they have a it's like I
don't know that is a pie in the sky and
that's naive so I'm not going to move
that way I'm not gonna move towards that
and so I anything that moves us towards
that way of being for me is a beautiful
future and I don't know what it's gonna
look like in the animal it's gonna feel
like it's gonna feel like that feeling I
have when I say when I have you know
this yeah this feels right and it feels
right because intuitively it's picking
up on everything and we we just know
it'll be better for us now better first
and if you did better for everybody else
you know that's
that's what I envisioned and I it's
gonna come from things like this that
you're doing Jubilee and other people
are coming a billion approaches that
just feel like this feels right awesome
thanks mark
Carlin did you want to show your version
of the future or I can also share mine
by my version of game B when I came as
the game bSpace the idea of a technology
cooperative that we all own together it
had empowers us to live our best lives
but doesn't have power over us and it's
still very much in alignment with what I
want to create in the world and at the
same time exactly what Mark talked about
like us all having that that feeling
that pulls us towards our version I am a
bit of a utopian and listening one of
Jamie I think with Jamie wheels videos
talking about how utopia is never
possible because if you what is the word
if you try to maximize one value it's
always gonna cost you everything else
and so although that seems like it
breaks utopia to me it actually makes it
because it means that if I have my
maximum value I don't know what maximum
value is love and justice and safety and
then whatever my maximum is if I'm
living towards that I don't get to
control everyone and make that the
maximum but I get to hold that for me
and everyone else holding their maximum
value means that we actually do weave
together towards proto PIA we're always
looking for ways to maximize it and you
can't maximize it for one person and so
my version of game B is people having
access to tools to be able to co-create
solutions for themselves with people
what is a way that 10,000 people can
come together and create something and
then they have it for themselves and
they can offer it to the rest of the
world and there's the less we're focused
or I'll talk about myself the less I'm
focused on trying to change other people
and trying to change the world to be my
vision the more I can actually just
create it with people who share that Co
vision who share like oh yes I want a
better food system
instead of making the world have to
follow my food system how do I have
better access to food in a way that
empowers you know the other 9,999 people
and then hopefully also the world
without imposing it on them and so that
is my vision of a future and I think
it's much more attainable and okay if
it's like generations in the future I'm
like five 10 years actually once we
start this process
everything starts domino eat and falling
together and when people have the
ability to come together and create
solutions they come together and create
solutions then we get access to all
those solutions and our lives improve
and then we have more to give to the to
the Commons and if it's the voluntary
and not forced its payments in and of
itself to find yourself in this space
with people who care and projects that
are amazing and watch it weave together
so that is my baby thanks Jubilee Linda
do you want to go next
I guess I mean my thoughts are kind of I
was finding myself like agree with mark
and Jubilee and you know a lot of things
they were saying just to guess the
perfect picture would to be in a place
where you know feels feels good you know
and feels right feels like this is this
is how it should it should feel to live
in a community like kind of how I feel
to live in my house but expand that to
like I feel safe and comfortable and
valued by my you know by the society
that I live in and I think that I like
that how Jubilee was talking about how
everyone can find like the solutions in
themselves you know first because then
if everyone brings their solution to the
table you know what they have their
strengths their knowledge and all that
to this one place then if you would have
like 10,000 of those people you would
have every you would have every idea
every ability that you could possibly
need to create a new society a new way
of living you know even if it was just
amongst each other and then other people
would see that and I think that the more
people are aware that this game be exist
cuz let me and my mom saw it we're like
this has been around we didn't even know
this that more people would agree with
that then wouldn't I think more people
are fed up with game a then are enjoying
it you know so that's wrong yes I got a
goal but this has been a wonderful
nice meeting guys for us sent you the
link after mark so we can talk for a bit
ten minutes before you need to switch
over to the last part of what what
emerged for you what other people are
talking what parts did you love about
other people's game be Carl wait did you
share your version of game be no no I
got I want to hear your beautiful
version I'll do my first I think oh it's
it's still pretty new for me and I guess
the things that feel wrong about the way
that things feel wrong about game a
probably a good place for me to start in
terms of what might that vision look
like I feel like the thing that that I
really want to solve is this I guess a
better way off
being together as a community and so I I
feel like the way that it's hard for me
to articulate how that might look from
like a descriptive point of view because
I don't know how that it's going to work
but I know that like conflict is normal
but like this kind of blindness that we
have two other points of view and the
sphere of losing losing fear of losing I
guess it kind of took this the best term
I have Furnaces kind of survival anxiety
so I suppose the counterpoint of that
would be that it's a future where people
feel safe and feel able to use their
creativity and to build something that's
meaningful to him rather than feeling
like somebody is keeping them from that
or somebody is going to take from them
[Music]
yeah I think that's it for me it's
really about allow creating in a a
society that allows people to give their
gifts and I'm very reluctant to kind of
be more specific because I don't sell
from solutions just yet powerful place
to be in I have to keep coming back to
it because I do think I have the
solution and I'm like let go of that
solution so I'm gonna actually emerge
into the world and like this weekend's
I'm doing this 36 questions to fall in
love and I'm like and that's it
like I'm like because my mind wants to
go into the 15 other steps that come
after like and then we can start forming
solution tracing group so then we kind
of like no just do people show up I mean
do people enjoy this experience and how
do we make it a better experience and
yeah learning to be in the emergence
what is that what is this
it's a New York Times article that was
written like a decade ago it's 36
questions then there's there in group
three groups of 12 and they get kind of
more and more intimate I've had about
six first dates but I'm honestly just
doing like we're doing this I wanted to
experiment what does it feel like to
answer these questions and I did it with
three men about six seven years ago and
then to do it with three women more
recently and it is powerful I never had
a second day because that wasn't kind of
the point but like having the experience
of seeing the person in front of you and
I think that is to me us and how we get
to game B I'm like I'm just gonna make
the world fall in love with each other
that's my diabolical plan
cuz once you love the person and like
once you practice falling in love with
human then you see you starts because
it's like you fall in love with one and
you like almost want to attach to them
right like oh you're a lovable person
and then you realize everybody's a
little person and you start to fall in
love much more rapidly like you just
follow the humanity and I think we're
currently doing the opposite it's like
fear and disconnect and it's really easy
to hate somebody on the other end of the
screen when you've never met them like
when this is harder right like it's
harder to actually just like someone
that you see on video but typed out it's
like I'm gonna put everything into what
you said I'm gonna I'm gonna make my own
judgments and I'm gonna put those on you
and we all do it and so you know both
the practice falling in love and that
there's this certain all of society is
set up for getting influenced finding
people to love you right like be this
celebrity and get millions of people to
love you then you'll be happy and like
no you won't because you don't love them
like you might love the mass of them but
you don't love them and you can be
cancelled and one person hurts your
feelings and you multiply that times
your million fans instead of like I have
a daughter who I love her to death
and she's like up to me like it's like I
could take you relieve you and I'm like
oh it doesn't matter
like what I get out of this relationship
is all the love I give not the love I
get and how much in my life
I was trying to it was a game right it's
like well I want you to love me and I
don't want to love
as much as you love me so that I'd like
somehow winning they're like no that's
not just love it doesn't matter if the
other person loves you just love it pays
for itself that's how you get oxytocin
is by giving not getting love and so
finding ways to create connection that
are what is the word not broadcast that
are interconnected that are like we
being together like how do we have like
a cult without a cult leader like give
people everything they get out of that
without having it reliant on one person
and one set of beliefs it's connection
together so it's kind of like practice
and presence yeah yeah without needing
to it's litter it's just answering these
36 questions like would you like to come
to dinner with how is your relationship
with your mother or what was your best
version it's and it's not my 36
questions it's designed for this process
and maybe together we will create one
that's even more more powerful and
hopefully create a social media platform
that does this and connects people but
that's the next steps it's like are
people showing up do they want this is
it giving them something that they
didn't they didn't get before I feel
like I've tainted the next section
there's a whole other parallel one going
on yeah I think that's a great idea and
I think now like this whole climate they
were literally living in now because of
the cove in 19 because of the just that
the everything right now that is causing
us to be disconnected from each other I
think more now people are watching that
they're wanting to feel close to other
people somehow and feel accepted you
know so I think that now seems to
probably be like an optimal time like if
you're ever gonna get an opportunity
this might be the perfect one to really
get people involved with this game the
idea now because game a has you know put
a lot of them you know
out of out of work out of relationships
out of you know and so yeah yeah kind of
chink in the game a armor for me is I
guess a lack of the money which is kind
of what you were saying like people
don't feel connected and maybe that's a
big-city thing I don't know like a sense
of disconnection I feel like if you
could offer that through again be I
think a lot of people would give up a
pretty big chunk of the existing life to
get that yeah to me that is the omni
wind solution and it's something that is
like so close and yet so far away like
it's what we it's the reason we're on
social media getting dopamine hits as we
want that connection and so if you give
people something that actually gives
them connection I don't think we choose
just endlessly scroll through our
Facebook feeds even if we also chase
that right again yeah this part of it
like I think that's why we're addicted
to cat videos is if you do get a bit of
the oxytocin because they're cute and
it's like well what about fall in love
with a human like what about trend the
more you do it the more you get you get
to realize all humans are actually
amazing there's very few that aren't and
I think we get the opposite message as
I've said it's like I constantly see
stupid horrible people in the media I've
yet to meet one in real life run like
face to face online keep we're not we're
not ignorant bring beautiful intelligent
people who care and even if we're racist
homophobic hustles that's a tiny sliver
of who we are and if we concentrate on
that it seems to grow or is if we can
love people around that like it's better
stuff emerges and like right now with
racism and stuff that's going on in the
state so like I feel yeah tearing out
the statues it's hard at the same time
as somebody with a disability work in
the same news news broadcasts like oh
whatever coab it only kills only kills
people with disabilities it only kills
I'm like you're literally calling
for my death but I get that you're not
like you don't actually want me to die
you just don't see my beauty and
capacity because you see me as a cost to
society and not giving and yet I can see
everybody giving and so seeing that what
happens when we start to tap into that
like we don't actually need the world to
do it we just need enough people to
start doing it and then you know and by
friends like it was this fun comeback
more people and that brings us to the
half an hour mark which we can now
switch over into the best part my
favorite part which is the the adjacent
possible what is it we could actually do
with 10,000 people and $100,000 and it
doesn't need to be that like structured
sometimes it gets a little bit bigger
than that sometimes it's definitely
smaller than that like game B itself
only has less than 2,000 people in the
Facebook group but yeah what could we do
if we were trying to create game be
10,000 people everyone put in $10 now we
have $100,000 what can we do to
powerfully move our game B forward my I
I think that well because it's it's
newer to me my mind can kind of think
more like at this moment when there's
like 2,000 people in it and I think that
somehow spreading awareness that this
exists would quickly come up with the
the numbers you know I'm not sure why it
was hard to find I don't know because I
feel like me my mom for a year is would
like Google like alternative society
ways of different things and we just we
actually we came upon it because it just
popped in our YouTube feed you know we
and so I don't know if like what ways
you guys will be open to like
advertising the the idea like just
letting people know this actually this
actually exists people actually are
thinking about this cuz if you go to you
know a club or a you know how people
have groups well now it's harder to find
because they're separated you know
because of the Cova 19 but somehow reach
out to communities especially like poor
the poorer communities they're going to
be really attracted to this this idea
you know they're coming from a place
where they can't leave their house
because there's people shooting or
they're they're afraid to you know
they're they're afraid of the police
they're poor they can't they feel
trapped and they are longing for a place
where that's safe and they can feel
accepted and they would be you know
willing to put everything they had you
know their abilities even if they had no
money but they had the ideas and the the
will you know to do it to say I'll do I
can do this for you or you know you'll
cook you'll just find people with all
these skills and all these like
beautiful intentions for this society
it's just that they really don't know it
exists so I don't know if that can be a
way to make it make the numbers multiply
faster you know to get it going cuz it
seems like I'm not sure how many
it's been years the game be has been
around but it still hasn't lifted off
the ground you know it just doesn't have
the people lament
because I feel like this game be it
really without the people it's it's not
gonna go anywhere like you need a mast
the mass is too to be be behind you and
so it has to be some way to get that
going and I don't really know how you
know um this would be you know achieve
but um I don't know I just that's all my
thoughts are right now yeah what I want
to ask is is if which I'll ask after if
Carl is is what if we had the ten
thousand like right now everyone signed
up and we have ten thousand now what do
we do with them and that because that is
what I want to cut like personally I
want to concentrate on is like being one
of the administrative entities and
people in there it's already hard enough
to like it's not designed for that right
so like what would it look like to
design something that ten thousand
people could come together and create a
solution and that's solution raising a
process raising that I'm working on
adjacent to it but like what do we do
now that we have ten thousand people I
guess it's kind of like the question for
me is is it's like do you do something
that is like so great like for example a
builder it's a terrible idea
but you build a social network of some
sort right and then you know you've got
a I've got a better than Facebook social
network that delivers connection or
whatever it is or is it something
there's more subtle than that
where are you saying you know you've got
ten thousand people who can promote an
idea that's more like
getting people to really examine what a
good life looks like for them where they
ever a meaningful unfulfilled life what
do they need to have them and to kind of
create a movement around disengaging
from conspicuous consumption and
disengaging from or making a conscious
choices that move them towards a life
that they think is meaningful which is
something that we just and then then I
guess like that you wouldn't even need a
hundred thousand dollars right you just
as an idea so yeah I guess like I guess
I'm gravitating more towards something
like that where it's like it's a we need
a mindset shift right and the mindset
shift has to cut has to come from like
seeing things I haven't given you an
idea but that's that's found that the
emergence of it is I love the idea of
10,000 people coming together and
figuring out for themselves what they
need to play game be like what do they
need to feel safe enough that they can
create an omni wind society for
themselves and then i think those people
especially when they come in at the
beginning are going to naturally be
committed to creating it for the rest of
the world like you don't just stop with
yourself but you do i think he just
start with yourself and i think that's
part of what's lacking in the social
justice part everyone i know who's done
that including myself it's burnt out so
fast because it's like your charity and
your you know you mean like people are
reliant on you and then you have to keep
continually give it to them instead of
like how do we teach people to fish how
do we actually start listening and be
like because everyone knows what they
need they don't need someone coming in
and saving them they need to be heard
and to be able to be joined up with
other people and be like how do how do
we you know finding food how do i also
get you food how do we do it together
how do we create these things um one
thing i think especially if you had that
many people you're right you can't have
10,000 people
one Facebook page like that would be
insane or in one one place that would be
insane but because we are spread out if
there was some way for people such as I
live in San Diego if I somehow knew
where the other game people were in San
Diego the people in San Diego could come
up with solutions and work on like
themself in their own individual like
like almost like small groups teaching
each other how to fish so that it it
wouldn't be on write like like a couple
people just draining themselves you know
um so if that could be a way for to
break up into smaller groups with common
with this common goal it would I think
that would spring up more solution you
know and then the the groups could you
know come together and you know are
representatives of the groups like with
ten thousand people maybe you would have
a hundred or way more than one hundred
girls you'd probably have like I don't
know like eight hundred groups with on
they're all over the word
world right and then east group could
just have like representative like well
this is what our group is working on
this is this and um help break it down
and I think maybe one thing that game a
has that makes sense is an
organizational structure of how to
communicate with each other dealing with
a large group of people so yeah if you
have ten thousand people you have to
have some sort of Jessa make it
manageable somehow so I'm not sure if
you guys already have have found a
solution for that and I just don't know
what yeah you're in the process of
figuring out a solution for that it's
like we have all these ideas you could
create with ten thousand people a
hundred thousand dollars now how do you
actually create any of them with ten
thousand people then how do you get ten
thousand people I have a lot of ideas of
how we could create with ten thousand
people based on my experience but it's
about doing it right like how do you
create something of a hundred people
okay so made like right now is there's
two of these going on right now right
this is the first time that's happened
my dream is that this is there's
hundreds of people around the world
having solution ratings on the same
topic every week and then we we submit
what are those ideas are and vote on our
favorite one you have ten thousand
people if you had ten thousand people
participating all putting in ten dollars
a month
twenty five hundred conversations a week
we would have a powerful solution for
food and energy and you know and you
would have the connection locally
because you even if I'm having a
conversation with people globally about
food I'm probably connecting with people
locally and in my area for it and some
solutions you need local ten thousand
people in some solutions you need global
ten thousand people and welcome Alex
if you missed the first the first part
we talked about what game a was a bit
and our game be versions of the future
and now we're talking about we can
actually create with 10,000 people and
$100,000 for game B itself and it's it's
funny because coming into the game B
Facebook group myself in September and
now it's kind of designed to be chaotic
like it's designed to be like right
there is no 101 here now you
understand game B because it's I always
laugh cuz it's like let me just catch up
I'm like with the 50 series of a baekje
serie like all of Jordan stuff like even
just keeping up with them and then you
get into the space of like oh they're
not game B we're game B and so you need
to make your own connections and have
conversations and create projects and
figure it out from the ground up and
it's a very that having a way that
people don't need to intellectually get
what game B is they can just start
playing it you know that I think the
beauty of it is that it's simple game a
is here and broken and we need a game B
even if we don't agree what that is and
there's certain antivirus Omni when
infinite game but how do people come on
board with their own passion and their
own vision and actually jump in how do
we create lives that work for them so
they can do that and that to me is what
I'm looking at is like how do I create a
life right now with Kobe 9 I'm pretty
set I'm pretty good now I'm like I don't
want to live in the city I want to move
out into like I don't know rural queer
utopia where people are working on tech
projects doesn't exist so I'm just gonna
hold that is a vision in the future with
a third kids oh it's like you sorry
there's people doing it yeah no there's
definitely a lot of this value just by
the fact that people can't really meet
each other and they need to be working
there and like you know it's some me
somebody shifted all that everyone being
like actually really like to have some
open space so I'd like to actually have
some more room in the places that I live
so I think some some projects like that
that's that's that's what I'm hoping to
work on seeing as Mars is it's something
where you could have shift shift the
people out it was just into doing the
halls
sibian projects that's that's very much
the same thing so trying to get like a
meeting it's just figuring out what is
the what is the what is the the gold of
these wire people there and and then how
can we come just bring that outside
[Music]
nature
is there a repository of ideas because
there people are coming up let's make
this cheaply you've got loads of ideas
if you have you well I'm not and this is
what I can do is have a video
conversation I also have like a dock
that I just trying to keep updated with
all the fires I'm starting but no I mean
there's game be projects as far as
people who have their own project who
are like looking for people to come
collaborator we're looking to create on
you win solutions and there's a lot of
people trying to compile like the game
be stuff right like Jordan halls and
Daniel Stockton burgers and and their
stuff but no we don't have a way that's
part of like creating that what game BT
right is happy when you come in and it's
chaotic how do you make it a little less
chaotic without needing it to be your
version of non chaos right like it's
like well read this do this isn't gonna
work no that's like that's a 101 lesson
you know like game be 101 now we now you
can pass the test
move on to the next phase there isn't a
test right it's it's for me anyway it's
like learn what you want to learn and
then when you're in conversation with
someone you both bring all of that
information to it one of the things I
think would be very powerful to create
for game B there's a woman she just died
a few weeks ago named Barbara shear and
she has a really amazing TED talk out
there and she talks about how it's not
poverty really that keeps us as
impoverished but our lack of connection
and she has this idea called wish
obstacle which gets people together and
you say but your wishes and what your
obstacle is stopping it when there's a
large enough people a group of people
generally somebody has the exact
solution to your obstacle like literally
there's people who are like I want to
move to a horse ranch and be like I want
to live move to queer utopia right like
someone has that so he's like actually
yeah out in nature and there's kids
running all right yes here you go um so
something like that that people were
able to like Pinterest where we actually
help each other create it like it's like
oh you want a tiny house and I want a
tiny house let's find 10,000 people to
create tiny houses so they're not
$50,000 and they're you know cheaper
because we're doing it together and
finding ways to just even just for
people who have a common common vision
and hey you can help each other better
than doing it all on your own yeah
because I feel like the bicep I sort of
pulling pulling those sort of systems
together if you just go like okay how do
I make a tiny house and then you've got
all of you know most of the stuff you
can kind of almost like this there's
instructions out there there's like you
know a lot of this stuff is open-source
already and if you can if they can just
get into that process of being like okay
I want this and enough people have
already said that they want the same
thing then it can just be easily
directed to the process and one will
hear it here's all that all of the stuff
like this is everything you need this is
your blueprint like we can go ahead and
we can connect you up with all the
people that you might need to help with
it as well cuz I mean Google is not
enough really
that's SEO build shared processes with
other people yeah I do feel the more I
sit with like my solutions the more
they're already out there they're just
not connected like every idea of had
they're like oh yeah so and so I'm like
right but they're not connected and
they're not we don't own them together
and we don't and we don't necessarily to
own them together but at least knowing
when somebody creates something instead
of reinventing the wheel is there a
reason to reinvent that wheel
what is that's not doesn't work for the
rest of us in that and maybe it's just
that it is for profit and we can't
recreate it ourselves
but there's so much so much and it is
we've been together even just in the
game be space this kind of reminds me of
something I've noticed with the with the
code that outbreak was was seeing a lot
of projects that we're all kind of doing
the same thing and you know because all
of the needs are very spread and like
there's no organizations that are there
to solve these
or needs they just kind of everyone just
springs up trying to solve it wherever
they are in there like they don't know
about each other so they're all trying
to do the same thing and then you just
have like a whole bunch of these
different communities of people that are
all kind of doing similar some of the
things some of them overlap and and just
coming into it from like okay one of you
all of you people are doing this like
for nothing like you're just doing it
for the good of solving the problem but
it's getting them to actually like
combine it is actually very difficult
it's like everyone's attached like a
brand on it
ego attached to it and then it just
becomes it even if there's no sort of
you you know they're not even motivated
by money it's like by the fact that it's
theirs it's you know that less willing
to kind of like share it with other
people which i think is kind of
interesting interesting things consider
when we sort of want what we want to
collaborate with people suddenly just
buys you then it's done you don't have
to like it doesn't matter you've got
like a transaction worse if it's
something mutual so the more may be
complicated and that is a big a big
issue is that what we notice we came to
game be as everyone has their own
project and no one wants work on someone
else's everyone's people to work on
there's more like well then let's work
from there now if we bring people
together and create on new in solutions
for our projects which is gonna be
projects or together tech but that we
need to own that like even in my own
it's like I want everyone to come on
boards mind but that's still the same
thing even though mine is more open it's
like no literally just come and have a
conversation
it really can come and be on board but
there's still like some less I work out
the path the less attached by onto that
path right so literally just taking the
next step and then seeing who wants to
come on board and recreate the next step
and the next step is a big piece of it
but it's chaotic but wait no I want the
path like I could giving you one and
then we're gonna absolutely not follow
it I saw another page when I was looking
for this one is called I can't remember
if it's a call game be
communities or game beep might have been
game be projects I don't remember but
what are those pages that are broken
down to more specific like game be
associated things people are doing in
certain places or yeah here's like a
dozen there's so there's game be
Facebook group without a space game be
no space then there's game space be home
page which links to all of the subgroups
and anyone can start a subgroup as long
as I think Jim Roth has to be one of the
amends that he can attach it to the main
page and yes there's communities which
are people trying to start physical
communities there's conversations which
I think just went blank I think they
might not they might have I don't know
if they delete it or what Cuba 2.0
there's game be projects there's like
literally there's there's one on social
media one on map II and and one on the
game be wiki which are pretty connect
like it's just people slice flavors of
it right and tools that we can use
online and so basically anything that
doesn't fit into someone else's
someone's created one but they are
connected by the home page but there's
2,000 people in the Facebook group and
only about 200 I think have liked the
home page and then founds the the other
other pieces so and that only started in
January or February so it's not very old
and there's already that many then I've
sparked it up and like people get kicked
out of the main game B page but they
don't get picked kicked out of like you
can't kick you don't kick someone or to
gave me it's just not possible
it's like right you you can't so but
they could get themselves kicked out of
all the various ones but that would take
do you think like the coordination
problem is something that needs to be
solved or do you think that it's one of
these emergent things where we just keep
running as fast as we can and the
compass will the coordination problem
will go away just through if
I think it's a problem we need to solve
but it's whose to solve whose whose is
it to solve right like I have solutions
that I don't know how to code them I
don't know how to create them I don't
know how to actually and so it's
something about like the person who has
the time and efforts bill to actually
create it creating it in a way that it
works for everybody else because if
they're creating it just for themselves
it's gonna be a solution just for
themselves which is there's tons people
like oh I have my social media platform
we should use that instead of Facebook
like we didn't create it together it
doesn't have our needs together like
there isn't there's something about
creating it together if someone can come
on board with the skill take collective
information of like here's what we
looked in that and then actually make it
but who's gonna do that
that's like give me assignments to do
right it's more vision you have the
passion so figuring out how do we
co-create something together so it's our
vision and our passion and then maybe
pool money to pay the person to create
it if it's a full-time job
or yeah I mean I guess the other side of
that is like we run into this design by
committee issue where we have 10,000
people who all have slightly different
ideas of what a solution might be and
you kind of I mean there's probably a
half a dozen people who are already
building social networks and it's like
well social network isn't really a thing
we think I think we need is coordination
so maybe the the less traditional way of
approaching that challenge so instead of
getting our requirements together and
then trying to figure out how we
coordinate maybe it's like let five or
ten people go away and come up with ways
of coordinating and leave it open and
then the one that works the best
it's kind of it's it's game a but it's
it does that doesn't that doesn't make I
mean especially if there's gonna be
people that are that are working on it
to get it to that stage and then to sort
of compare compare them with everyone
else that's probably gonna mean it like
multiple people are going to be putting
in thing at the time and then after that
it might get a bit like disillusioned if
they if they don't get paid sooner me if
it's like a competition thing but I
think that's a good that's a good point
in terms of like how we could get get
people you know allow can get people we
don't want to give them permission to go
at the same time like you know they
should feel empowered to go and do it
but at the same time it's you know if
you go and spend time on something make
it and then and then put it out there
and then people don't use it and then
you're gonna feel like you've wasted
your time so you almost need some kind
of like okay yes we like where this is
going keep going type of thing almost
like a bit of a proposal sort of
scenario maybe coming down to the last
few minutes yes I think we need a July
Lucian's which means unfortunately the
tech people who know how to create the
tech L they no agile they'd actually
don't know how to create agile solutions
with the communities and the community
that's really good at giving it like all
I want to do is create the platform for
doing what I'm doing this weekend but
even if I create it even if someone
spent thousands of dollars and created
it I don't know if people like it I
don't know if people want to show up and
actually do it and so it's it's it's
finding non tech ways and current tech
ways to try and play in this space while
we create how do we connect how do we
understand what's going on how do we
bring people so that they're they're not
feeling like they're creating a game a
corporation they're creating a contest
right like we need color a coloring
thing and you submit it you don't expect
to win if it's part of a contest you're
like oh this is fun I want to have a
conversation right and you're not
putting in thousands of hours you're
putting in an hour of a conversation or
you're putting in you know six hours on
a Saturday working and drawing something
out but you know that the point is is
the bigger the bigger picture
I think there are ways as long as we're
open to the plane in it right like what
would make you want to do that without
necessarily being picked the winner how
do you make the game fun itself and so I
just wanna give everyone a chance to
wrap up their thoughts if they would
like before stopping the broadcast and
then I'm gonna go to the other one so I
can stop there I am more strict on time
today than I have been in the past yeah
okay I'll finish up to me I I guess it's
made me realize that the key here
justice if you've got an idea then the
thing that's needed is just same but I
like what you said at the end there
about kind of doing it in a playful way
because I think the critical bet here is
like keeping this light and allowing
people to bring themselves to the
conversations and they don't and that's
easily done when you're you approach her
in a playful and creative way um I guess
my final thoughts I'm really happy that
I found this is there usually a set time
that you will host these types of
virtual group meetings or would they
just be like randomly or is it usually
like a certain day of the week or
something like that
I hold solution ratings at 9:00 a.m. my
time on Wednesdays the same time every
week there is its own Facebook group
which is inside to Game be called
solution raisins where I definitely post
them and then when they feel more game
be relevant I'm I think I'm gonna post
more and more in game B because they're
all relevant I mean how are any of them
not relevant it's you actually creating
it when it is a way to come together
there's also like my individual schedule
that I try to put up or eat every Sunday
but it ends up being Monday these days
where you can follow like the solution
raising be together tech stuff because
I'm in a lot of different groups and
then other ones that other
process racing is in its infancy and
people aren't invited to that at the
moment yeah I can send you the link to
solution areas if you want they might
not be on YouTube anymore because if
this works and we're gonna have more
parallel I might be paying for a zoom
accounts and holding them on Zoom and
then breaking out into groups and
figuring it out for that land which is
more powerful I can't wait to watch the
other one see the part that I was not
involved in at all and see how they come
up with
yes well thank you thank you very much
and I have like some co-workers I can
just immediately think off the top of my
head that I have conversations like this
with and I'm definitely going to let
them know that something actually exists
with you know what we talked about you
know on our downtime so thank you thanks
for joining everybody I'm just gonna say
goodbye to YouTube now